A Guide to the Papers of Paul T. David
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Paul T. David
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12793-b
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Contents List
- Administration of Foreign Affairs and Overseas Operations Research Files 1946-1954
  - General Records:
    - Other Agencies 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Agriculture Department 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - --Relations with International Agencies 1950 (Box 1)
    - Air Mail 1950 (Box 1)
    - American Political Science Association 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Antioch College 1950 (Box 1)
    - Atomic Energy Commission 1950 (Box 1)
    - Ballantine Memoranda 1950 (Box 1)
    - Books 1950 (Box 1)
    - Budget for Project 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Budget Bureau--Interviews 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Bureau of the Budget 1950 (Box 1)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board 1950 (Box 1)
    - Clippings 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Commerce Department 1950 (Box 1)
    - Congress and Foreign Affairs 1950 (Box 1)
    - Connery--Europe Trip 1950 (Box 1)
    - Consultants 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Cooperating Agencies 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Council of Economic Advisers 1950 (Box 2)
    - David--Europe Trip 1950 (Box 2)
    - --Manpower Institution Paper 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - --Personal Correspondence 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - December Report 1950 (Box 2)
    - Defense Department 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Displaced Persons Commission 1951 (Box 2)
    - Documents Center 1950 (Box 2)
    - Economic Cooperation Association 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - --Brookings Bulletin Article 1951 (Box 2)
    - ECOSOC 1950 (Box 3)
    - EOP 1950 (Box 3)
    - European Trips--Correspondence 1950 (Box 3)
    - Executive Office of President 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - Export Control 1951 (Box 3)
    - Export-Import Bank 1951 (Box 3)
    - Food and Agricultural Organization 1950 (Box 3)
    - Federal Communications Commission 1950 (Box 3)
    - Federal Security Agency 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - Final Report 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - --Agency Comments 1951 (Box 3)
    - --Distribution 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - --Revision 1951 (Box 3)
    - Foreign Economic Assistance Study by Brookings 1950 (Box 3)
    - Foreign Missions in Washington 1950 (Box 3)
    - Foreign Services, State Department 1950 (Box 3)
    - Forms n.d. (Box 3)
    - Gange, John 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - Gordon Gray Report 1950 (Box 3)
    - Gosnell Article 1950 (Box 3)
    - Haviland Memoranda 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Hearings 1951 (Box 3)
    - Hoover Commission Recommendations by Departments and Agencies 1949 (Box 3)
    - ICAO 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Index to Interview Memoranda 1950 (Box 4)
    - Information Program 1950 (Box 4)
    - Interior Department 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Organization and Specialized Agencies 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Bank 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Labor Organization 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Monetary Fund 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Supply Memo n.d. (Box 4)
    - International Telecommunications Union 1950 (Box 4)
    - International Trade Organization 1950 (Box 4)
    - Justice Department 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Koenig Memorandum 1950 (Box 4)
    - Labor Department 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Labor--Relations with International Agencies 1950 (Box 4)
    - Mutual Defense Assistance Program 1949-1951 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda--Staff 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Miles, Carroll F. 1950 (Box 4)
    - Miller Memoranda 1950 (Box 4)
    - Minutes of Staff Meetings 1950 (Box 5)
    - Mutual Security Program 1951 (Box 5)
    - NSRB 1951 (Box 5)
    - National Advisory Council 1950 (Box 5)
    - National Defense and Security 1950 (Box 5)
    - National Planning Association 1951 (Box 5)
    - National Security Council 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Association 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - Occupied Areas 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - Office of Alien Property 1950 (Box 5)
    - Office Procedures 1950 (Box 5)
    - Owen--Europe Trip 1950 (Box 5)
    - Personnel 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - Personnel--Inactive 1950 (Box 6)
    - --General 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Burr, Janet 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Cohen, Sonia R. 1951 (Box 6)
    - --Connery, Robert H. 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Curry, Harriet B. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --David, Paul T. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Fink, William E. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Guill, Mrs. Grace L. 1948-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Harrison, Thelma W. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Haviland, H. Field 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Hyneman, Charles S. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Langston, Mrs. Kathryn 1951 (Box 6)
    - --Mathews, Dorothy M. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Meck, John F. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --McCamy, James L. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Miller, J. Clayton 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Marx, Fritz Morstein 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Noble, Dale 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Owen, Wilfred 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Packer, Earl 1950 (Box 6)
    - --Padelford, Norman J. 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - --Remer, C. F. 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - --Rubin, Seymour J. 1950 (Box 7)
    - --Sayre, Wallace 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - --Semmerling, Helen 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Project Contract 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - --Staff 1950 (Box 7)
    - Public Administration--Clearing House 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - --Committee on Case Studies 1950 (Box 7)
    - --Review 1950 (Box 7)
    - --Regional Organization and Arrangements 1950 (Box 7)
    - Rowe Committee Report and Materials 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Rubin--Mexico Trip 1950 (Box 7)
    - State--Interviews 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - --Department 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Security Council 1950 (Box 7)
    - Somers, Herman Miles 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Space 1950 (Box 8)
    - State--Relations with International Agencies 1950 (Box 8)
    - --Reorganization 1951 (Box 8)
    - Stockpiling 1950 (Box 8)
    - Supplies and Equipment 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Tasks Memorandum 1950 (Box 8)
    - Thurber, Clarence E. 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Thurber--Europe Trip 1950 (Box 8)
    - Thompson, E. Mathew 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Treasury Department 1946-1951 (Box 8)
    - Trusteeship Council 1950 (Box 8)
    - United Nations 1950 (Box 8)
    - UNESCO 1950 (Box 8)
    - Universal Postal Union 1950-1951 (Box 9)
    - Wallach, Maximilian 1950 (Box 9)
    - Wallach Memoranda 1950 (Box 9)
    - Walton, Wesley 1950-1951 (Box 9)
    - White House Staff 1950-1951 (Box 9)
    - WHO 1950 (Box 9)
    - Wilson, Robert 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Brookings Institution:
    - Haviland, H.F.--International Organizations 1950 (Box 9)
    - Program Planning--Government 1952-1953 (Box 9)
    - Purpose and Program Memorandum 1953 (Box 9)
    - Advisory Committee--Agenda and Conference 1953 (Box 9)
    - Committee on Political Parties--Buffalo Meeting 1952 (Box 9)
    - --General Correspondence 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Papers--Soldier Voting, Manpower Institute:
    - Completed 1950 (Box 9)
    - United States and International Organizations 1951 (Box 10)
    - Manpower Institute Papers 1950-1951 (Box 10)
    - Soldier Voting 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Reports:
    - Report on Multilateral and Bilateral Patterns of Negotiation and Action 1950 (Box 10)
    - Administration of Foreign Economic Aid Programs 1950 (Box 10)
    - National Security Council 1950 (Box 10)
    - United States Foreign Information Programs 1950 (Box 10)
    - Central Coordination and Direction of Military and Economic Aid 1950 (Box 10)
    - The Pattern of the U.S. Representation Overseas and at International Agencies 1950 (Box 11)
    - Problems of Personnel Administration in the Military and Economic Assistance Programs 1950 (Box 11)
    - Report on the Constitutional Distribution of Power in Respect to Foreign Affairs 1950 (Box 11)
  - Administration of Foreign Affairs and Overseas Operations:
    - Brookings Report 1951 April (Box 11)
    - Staff Reports, Articles and Memos 1950-1951 (Box 11)
    - Brookings Report 1951 June, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Survey of the Administration 1950-1951, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Contract and Annex 1950 (Box 12)
  - Administration of American Military and Economic Aid:
    - A Preliminary Report... 1950 December (Box 12)
    - Administrator's Memorandum 1946-1950 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Materials--Federal Budget:
    - Projects, Reports and Studies 1950-1954 (Box 13)
    - Decision Making and Action Process in the Department of State 1950 March, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Metz Study of Budget 1952-1954 (Box 13)
    - The Budget of the United States Government 1952-1953 (Box 13)
  - Administration of Foreign Affairs:
    - Packer Originals 1950-1951 (Box 14)
    - Working Papers 1950 (Box 14)
    - Noble--Occupied Areas Administration 1950 (Box 14)
    - Organization Chart--GER 1950 (Box 14)
    - Denazification 1949 (Box 14)
    - Organization Chart--EUCOM 1948 (Box 14)
    - HICOG Delegation 1949-1950 (Box 14)
    - Somers on Coordination Problem 1950-1951 (Box 14)
    - Basic Law and Occupation Statute 1950 (Box 14)
    - SCAP Reorientation 1947-1950 (Box 14)
    - McCloy Testimony 1950 (Box 14)
    - Committee Handbook 1950 (Box 14)
    - Exploratory Study and Recommendations on Civil Affairs and Military Government 1950 (Box 14)
    - Index--Materials for December Report 1950 (Box 14)
    - Trust Project 1950 (Box 14)
    - Staff Committee on December Report 1950 (Box 14)
    - Agriculture 1950 (Box 14)
    - Bureau of Budget 1950 (Box 14)
    - Civil Service Commission 1948-1950 (Box 14)
    - Commerce 1950, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Defense--Air Force 1950 (Box 14)
    - Defense--Army 1949-1950 (Box 15)
    - --Navy 1950 (Box 15)
    - Economic Cooperative Administration 1950 (Box 15)
    - Interior 1950 (Box 15)
    - State--Foreign Service 1945-1950 (Box 15)
    - --Departmental 1945-1950 (Box 15)
    - Treasury 1950 (Box 15)
    - Labor 1950 (Box 1)
    - Personnel--General 1949 (Box 15)
    - Working Papers--December Report 1950 December (Box 15)
    - Agency Comments on Drafts of Final Report 1951 (Box 15)
    - Outlines, Problems, Introduction, etc. 1951 (Box 15)
    - Chapters I-IX 1949-1951 (Box 15)